Guide to the Boy Scouts of America Collection of ephemeral material, 1838-1993
Department of Special Collections
Boy Scouts of America Collection of ephemeral material,
1838-1993
Special Collections M0855
Unknown
8.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1996.
Scope and Content
The ephemera in this collection was gathered from a Scouter's point of view, and includes materials which might have been collected over a lifetime career in scouting. The majority of the material in the collection reflects what a Scout leader or executive would want or require for successful organization and management of scouting activities, as well as career development. This includes brochures on better scouting, training materials, administrative paperwork, and inspirational posters and texts. There are several posters and calendars by well-known artists and Boy Scout supporters, Joseph Csatari and Norman Rockwell. Another area which is well-represented in the collection is newspaper articles and media and marketing materials. These include publications by scouting organizations as well as articles concerning the Boy Scouts. Additionally, information on major Boy Scout events is included in the collection. Unfortunately, the broker who sold the collection to the library lost the files which contained biographical information on the original collector of the BSA Ephemera during a relocation of the brokerage business. As a result, the original processor was responsible for the ordering and sequencing of all materials. This sequencing reflects the subject categories common to the organization of the Boy Scouts of America and the hierarchical order common to other finding aids.
Access Terms
Csatari, Joseph.; Rockwell, Norman.; Boy Scouts.; Scouts and scouting.
Container List
- Series I: General
  - "The Champ" Musical Comedy Program Nov. 23, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The President's Flag Day Address. Washington, D.C. 6/14/17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Veteran Scout Association enrollment letter from James E. West to D.B. Gottschall 2/16/32 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - National Council autographed letter from E.H. Vitalins to D.B. Gottschall 9/8/32 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter addressed to Hendrick Hudson Council Scoutmasters and Field Commissioners re: 14th Annual Roosevelt Pilgrimage 10/6/33 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Richard Kress inviting Dr. O.O. Larsen to Scout Leaders meeting 5/18/34 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Herbert H. Whetstone to Chief of Staff, BSA Headquarters, Kansas City, KA 8/21/35 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reading - A Gateway to Destiny. An Outline of Address by H.W. Hurt, Ph.D. at Chautauqua, NY July, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Our Children" by Angela Patri 12/27/40 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Boy Scouts of America encyclopedia entries 1950-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Valley Forge". An address by Col. Robert R. McCormick 1/7/50 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Scouting, The community's Weapon Against Crime". An Address by Hon. Miles F. McDonald, Kings County, NY 5/3/51 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - (2) Letters from Kenneth A. Wells to George H. Walper regarding BSA Research Service Cub Scouting Study 2/20/51 & 4/27/51 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Eagle Scout congratulatory letter from Arthur A. Schuck to Charles M. Morris 10/6/52 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Material on Soil and Water Conservation (ca. 1955-1960) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carl H. Jenson (material inside "Let's Go Camping!" - Nassau Caounty Council Camping Guide folder): (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Boy Scout Sunday: Order of Worship. Kings Highway Methodist Church, Brooklyn, NY 2/13/55 & 2/10/57 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Troop Roster 9/56 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Certificate of Commendation, Finance Campaign 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter of Certification for the Scouter's Award 1/22/57 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter of Presentation of Arrowhead Award 2/20/57 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter of Congratulations for the Chairmanship of the O & E Committee of the Kingsway District, NY 7/22/57 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Fellowship and Tribute Dinner: South East District. Saw Mill Road School, North Bellmore, NY 5/29/58 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Nassau County Council: Southeast District. Directory and Calendar of Events 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Nassau County Council: Southeast District. Commissioners Staff 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Nassau County Council: Se-Pequa District. Commissioners Staff (Box 1, Folder 5)
    1959-1960
  - YMCA Sunday Church Program n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Remarks by vice-President Humphrey. Johnston Historical Museum 5/13/65 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "To Whom It May Concern" letter confirming inhalator and resusatator training for Mr. Elwin Loke 1/20/71 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter of "thanks" from the Blue Water Council Executive Board to Mr. Jack Cambridge (addressed to Mr. Elwin H. Locke) 10/1/71 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Secretary of State Wesley Bolin to Col. Wesley S. Jones 1/7/74 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - World Brotherhood Exchange Bulletin 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Special Limited Inaugural Edition of the Constitution of the United States 1/20/89 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aquatic Camp letter and announcement n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Boy's Life Magazine advertisement n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Citizenship Educational Service, Inc. news release n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Col. Armstrong's Remarks n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - District Scout Executive Autobiography n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Envelope addressed to Leslie C. Stratton, BSA National Council n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Form greeting letter from Olave Baden-Powell to Career Scouters, Boy Power '76 Program Day, Scout Executive's Conference n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hammacher, Schlemmer & Co. Cabinet of Tools advertisement n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Assistant Secretary of Defense, Steuart L. Pittman to Scout Leaders re: Civil Defense n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Some Hints to Help You Win n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - What is a Boy? n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yonkers Council Benefit Variety Show bulletin n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Applications, Forms, and Lists
  - List of State Directors with telegram from Secretary McAdoo regarding Boy Scouts Third Liberty Loan Campaign 1918 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership Application Receipts to the "Good Old Scout" Organization. Fenimore Cooper Council, White Plains, New York (ca. 1920) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Strange's Dominion Headquarters for all Scout Equipment Price List (The Scout Gazette) 1/16/22 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Applications for Renewal fo Chapter for Local Council (Form 539-11-22-B.E.) (ca. 1922 & 1923) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Individual Scout Record. Lowry Air Scouts, Squadron 1 (ca. 1930) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yonkers Boy Scout Troops List (ca. 1932) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Application and Registration for Camp Tee-Tonk-Ah. Wolf Lake, MI (ca. 1933) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Troop Reports (Form 519-25M-4-31-D) (ca. 1935) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - District 4 Hendrick Hudson Council Program 3/12/36 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - General Camporal Schedule n.d.
    - Basis for Patrol Camping Rating n.d.
    - Camporal Suggestions to Judges n.d.
  - BSA Applications for Membership (Form C-501B-200M-1-38-D) 5/38 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - BSA Istrouma Area Council Program and Objective list - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Application To Become A Boy Scout (No. 4405) (ca. 1947) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hendrick Hudson Council Report to the Nation of the Scout Citizen at Work - 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fact Finding Work Books (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - At the District Level
    - At the Local Level
  - Volunteer Training Service Teaching Aids/Check Sheet Series (ca. 1948) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Woodworth Lake Scout Reservation Form for Order of the Arrow-The Ordeal Honor 1949 Council Fire Program Sheet 10/20/49 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Training Records (Cat. No. 4472) (ca.1950) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Unit Inventory of Training (Cat. No. 4482)
    - Training Events and Rountable Report: Three Year Training Program (Cat. No. 4483)
  - Official Scouter Titles (A-685) 9/5/52 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BSA Flint River Council Sales Receipt (ca. 1956)/Application for Explorer Unit Charter (Cat. No. 6190)/Separation Notice (No.6108)/Additional Enrollement for Explorer Units (No. 6168) (ca. 1957) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pack-Troop-Explorer Unit Advancement Report (No. 4417) (ca. 1957) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Troop Three Roster/Cookout Scoring Sheet/Script of Induction Ceremony 11/58 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Application for Permit to Conduct a Tour, Moving Camp, or Cruise (No. 4419) 11/59 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Report to Institution and the District/Division Committee (ca. 1959) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scouting Program Request (No.3069) 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Application for Registration Transfer (No. 6100) 2/60 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Application for Local Tour or Camp Permit (No. 4426) 8/61 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Training Record Supplement 8/61 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scout and Explorer Medical Record (No. 4126) 1/62 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Application for Camp Echockotee, Florida 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Application to Become a Boy Scout (No. 4405) 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter and Council Request Slip for "Family Alert" Civil Defense Information Packets 7/15/63 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Washington Irving Council district Commissioner's Monthly Data Sheet/Quarterly Work Sheet Analysis Nov.-Dec. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Application for Troop Charter (No. 6184) (ca. 1964) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pack Quarterly Work Sheet for Commisioners (No, 4170) 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Troop Quarterly Work Sheet For Commissioners (No. 4171) 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Application for Renewal of Local Council Charter (Form O-539) 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Region Six Monthly Goal Sheet (ca. 1967) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adventure Ahead: Silver Trails Scout Reservation Registration Folder 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Application For Transfer (No. 28-401)/Individual Cub Scout Record (No. 3827) (Elwin Locke ca. 1971) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baiting Hollow Scout Camp Forms 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Building Parent Participation /Parent talent Survey Sheet (No. 7362) 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Flag Order Form (No. 70-421) 2/77 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Troop Resource Survey (No. 4437) 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Troop Meeting Plan (No.4425) 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Webelos Den Meeting Program (No. 3852) 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Weekly Den Meeting Program Sheets (No. 3826) 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Personal Health and Medical Record Form 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Advancement Report (Pack, Troop, Team, Post, Ship) 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Buffalo Trail Col-Tex Aquatic Camp Reservation Form 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Additional Enrollment for Boy Scouts (No.6102) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Advancement Report (Pack-Troop-Explorer Unit) (No. 4403/No. 4417) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Advancement Report of Troop or Explorer Unit (Cat. No. 6200) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alabama Executives - Southeast Region n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Adult Registration Application (No. 28-501A) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Analysis of Unit Progress (No. 4818) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual Report of Troop Committee (Form O-1041-20M-2-38-A.P.) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Application for Adult Registration (No. 6115) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Application for Membership n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Application for Permit to Conduct a Scout Moving Camp, tour, Trip or Cruise n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Application For "Ready" Explorer Certification (No. 4403) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application For Registration in the Women's Reserve (No. 28-503) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application For Scout Life Guard (Cat. No. 6121/No. 4435) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application for Substitution for Basic Scout Requirements n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application for Substitution for Star or Life Rank Requirements (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application for Substitution for Swimming Requirement for First Class Rank n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application for Troop Charter (Form 690-10M-4-'20-[D.E.]) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application to Become a Boy Scout (Cat. No. 4405) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application to become a Den Chief (No. 4211) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Aquatic Advancement Record Card (No. 3406/3406A) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Books by Ernest and Julia Seton price list n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Boy Fact Survey n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Boy Scout Application (No. 8271C) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - BSA Relations Division. Scouting Information Request Card (No. 4-429) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - BSA Visual Education Service Recruiting Presentation film price list n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - College Scouter Reserve Application for Registration (No. 28-502) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Comments From Commisioner card n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Commissioner Work Sheet (No. 4125) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Scout Advancement n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Decision Form
    - Form Reference Letter
  - Council and Troop Order Sheet (Form 55-100M-5-35 D) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cub Scout Application (No.28-109) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cub Scout Den Record n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Daisy BB Gun Range order form n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Den Advancement Report n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Den Chief Conference Booklet checklist n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Den Record/Den Roster n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Den Record: Den Roster and Advancement n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - District Commissioner Staff Roster n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - District Nominating Committee Work Sheet (Cat. No. 6157) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Duties of Mothers in Each Den n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Equipment for Overnight Camping n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Family Camping order form n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Five, Ten, Fifteen or Twenty Tear Veteran Scout Application Blank (Form 598-10M-5-33-A) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Forward on Liberty's Team" District New Unit Charts n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Headquarters Gazette order form n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Heddon Fishing Education Starter Package order form n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Health and Medical Record (No. 4410) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Health and Medical Record for Youth (No. 4410) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Health History and Medical Examination Record for New Scouts (Form C-1154) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Historic Trails Program/The 50-Miler Program Application (No. 4408) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Home Fire Safety Check List n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - How to Obtain Refills for the Boy Scout Official First Aid Kit (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Information Sheet for All Interested in the Chartering of a Troop (Form 671 15M-5-2 [BE]) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Individual Boy Scout Record (No. 4406) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Inter-City Transfer Certificate (Form 502-100M-8-28-R.P.) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Leadership Transfer Notice (No. 28-508) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Local Council Nominating Committee Work Sheet (Cat. No. 6156) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Local Tour Permit Application for Trips and Camps Under 250 Miles (No. 4426) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Medical Examination By Registered Physician (Form C-952) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting Place Inspection Form (Cat. No. 6140) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - A Message For the Officer in Charge of Personnel - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - My Record In Scouting n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - NRA-BSA Annual Explorer Postal Rifle Match Entry Form n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Orienteering Course - Pratt Falls Score Sheet n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Our Camping Log - Application for the National Camping Award (No. 3690) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Please Invite Him Scouter postcard (No. 3831) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - A Plan for Local Council Inventory of Trained Leadership With Suggested Forms and Prospect Summary Sheets n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Record of Troop No./Attendance and Dues (Form 506 25M-8-37-D) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Renewal of Old Troops n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Request to Use the Scouting Program and Application for Unit Charters (Form No. O-1517) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rules and Regulations of Troop #118 n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Scout Application (No. 28-209) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Patrol Roster of ______ Patrol (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Personal Equipment List and Insignia List of Paul Lasher (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Scout Master Forms Packet n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Membership Application (F 501B)
    - Transfer Application (F 502)
    - Individual Records (F 503)
    - Attendance Dues (F 506-506A)
    - Merit Badge Applications (F 507)
    - Cash Records (F 509)
    - Additional Enrollment Blank (F 515)
    - Certificate of Tests Passed (F 525)
  - The Scout Oath n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scout or Cub Transfer Credit Certificate n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scout Tenure Record (Form 528 25M 3-34 K) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scouter Application (Form 716-100M-5-33-A) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sea Scout Application (Form 900-25M-4-34D) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Showando Equipment, Books and Pamphlets, and Boy's Life Reprint Booklets list n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Silversmithing Handicraft. Lawrence Bullard Craftwork Supplies Price List No. 1 n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Strengthen America 16mm motion picture order form n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sustaining Member/Contributions Form for the Detroit Area Council n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Paul Tavetian Army and Navy Goods Price List n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tawnee Reproductions Indian Neckerchief Slides and Necklaces price lists n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Transfer Application (Youth Member) (No. 28-401) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Troop Meeting Plan (No. 4425) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Troop Scouter Application (Form 716-50M-8-32-R) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Troop Sponsor, Chairman, and Unit Leader phone list n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Unregistered Unit Report (No. 28-403) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Veteran Application (No. 28-701) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Webelos Day At Camp Time Schedule and Schedule of Activities n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Webelos Den Meeting Program Sheets n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Webelos Den Record n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Weekly Den Dues Envelope (No. 4210) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Weekly Den Meeting Program (No. 3826 800M667) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Weekly Den Meeting Program (Cat. No. 4215) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Winchester BSA Commemoratives and Giftsware Order Form n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series III: Pamphlets, Guides, and Handbooks
  - The Scout Oath as a Basis for Character Ideals (ca. 1919) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stumbling Into Citizenship (ca. 1920) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Patrol Leaders From Old-Timers in Scouting 10/28 & 11/3/24 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - What Are the Elements of a Good Boy's Program? (ca. 1927) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1910 - An Idea, 1930 - 1,181,227 Members (ca. 1930) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Camping By Troops 4/8/36 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Booklet for Use in Connection with the Practical Course for Part II. of the Cub Wood Badge, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - First Aid Treatment of Snakebite 4/40 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Introductory Training Session 11/1/41 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Safety With The Belt Axe/The Fireman's Lift 12/41 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mother Goes Scouting 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 40 or More, Your Camping Score: A Bulletin on Better Programs for Boy Scout Camps. Region Two (ca. 1943) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - They Will Swim and Must Live - Here's How 5/44 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Demonstration Field in Camp 8/45 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Activity Field In Camp 10/45 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Archery Range/The Rifle Range 2/46 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Scout Law for Youth and Adults 5/24/49 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Instructions for Roll Call Officers (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Scouting, The Community's Weapon Against Crime" 5/3/51 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Survival" Information Leaflet June-July 1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Scouting in Action Fair" (ca. 1951) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jamboneering 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Safe Transportation 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Scout Distributor 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Who Pays for Scouting? 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Get Out the Vote" Campaign Kit 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Onward for God and My Country: A Guide for the Four-Year Program 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program for Butch: Program Division Emphasis for 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Some Significant Facts and Figures (ca. 1956) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Hi, parents! Glad you're with us - we welcome you to Troop" n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Patrol Dad in the Troop 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - What Boy Scouting Is 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Conservation Handbook: A Guide to Conservation Magic. Prepared for the Fourth National Jamboree, Valley Forge, PA 7/12-18/57 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - All Around the Town 1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Whole Scout Family (No. 4801) 1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Your Most Important Job - Securing a Cubmaster 1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Get-Out-The-Vote Publicity Kit 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 50 Years of Growing Strong to Serve America (ca. 1960) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 50 Years of Service to Boys (ca. 1960) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - America's Strength (ca. 1961) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Employee Benefit Specialist and His Job 11/28/61 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fall Boy Scout Rally (ca. 1962) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - How Scouting Dollars Serve 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Scout Camporee Guide 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Living in Camp - Camp Craft 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Follow the Rugged Road of Scouting (ca. 1965) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Home Office Tool Kit for District and Council Use 10/66 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Scouting Needs You 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Patrol Food Chest - assembly diagram n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Scouting Inner-City Style 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - PTA/BSA Successful Partners for Youth 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Parents's Guide to Scout Camping: The Great Adventure (ca. 1970) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Adult Leader Development. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Coach-Counselor Manual 1972
    - Unit of Training Skill Awards 1972
  - Boy Scout Leaders Training Materials 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - What Parents Should Know About Our Scout Troop 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Street Corner Scouting 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Tange Discusses Basic Knife Cuts 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - AMVETS Helps Boys Through Its Scouting Program! (ca. 1974) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conservation Program Highlights 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kayak Assembly Instructions. Desert Trails Council (ca. 1974) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - BOYPOWER Scouting Program (ca. 1976) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - BOYPOWER '76 Promotional Tools for Use With the Long-Range Plan (ca. 1976) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Spirit of '76 Campfire Program (ca. 1976) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Literature to Help Councils Serve Low-Income Areas 6/76 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Community Organizations and the Boy Scouts of America (ca. 1977) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 75th Diamond Jubilee Sustaining Membership Enrollment 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - New-Troop Organizer Kit 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Activities and Special Events "Ideas" File n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Boy Scout Skilloree
    - Dramatize Scouting with "Black Light"
    - Explorer First Aid Contest
    - "Indian Thunderbird Ceremonial" - A Scout Circus Act
    - An Inexpensive Scouting Mobile
    - Operation "Lost" - A District Emergency Mobilization Activity
  - All Boys n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - All Out For Scouting! n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Along the Trail at Lilacia Park - Lombard, Ill. n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - America's Future Lies In It's Youth n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)